

rkbk.sw.soldtons@gmaii.com | • minkobold | • minkob

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary _

Software engineer with 8+ years of experience.

Fast learner, always up for a challenge. Keen on understanding the low-level workings of tech and enjoying the grind of debugging.

Significant experience in FinTech Solutions, blockchain enthusiast. Interested in software performance and clean code.

Projects

- spinned up a custom stablecoin along with the necessary tooling (frontend, backend, DB)
- data verifiability solutions relying on blockchain technology
- financial applications and infrastructure supporting daily trading activities (at the following companies: TORA, ITIVITI, FlowTraders)
- developed a mathematical model and software for predicting the dynamics of the COVID-19 pandemic

Skills

smart contract languages Solidity, Rust

general purpose languages Java, Js, C#, groovy, Python, SQL **frameworks/tools** Spring Boot, YourKit, React.js, JUnit

ci/cd git, maven, gradle, Jenkins, Bamboo, Docker, Docker Compose

messaging Kafka, RabbitMQ

databases MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Apache Cassandra, SQLite

Operating systems Linux, MacOS, Windows

Experience

Weavechain

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT Jan. 2024 - Present

- design and implement in Rust a stablecoin contract on Casper Blockchain.
- · develop infrastructure (frontend for interacting with the blockchain, off-chain backend, database)
- Collaborate in identifying requirements and issues.. Keeping in touch with the smart contract auditing firm.
- Skills acquired: smart contract design and implementation, Rust language, REST API design, Docker.
- Technologies used: Rust smart contracts, Casper Blockchain, Casper Wallet, Java, PostgreSQL, Docker, Docker Compose, React.js

Weavechain

Senior Fullstack Engineer Mar. 2022 - Oct. 2023

- worked on Weavechain, a distributed system leveraging blockchain technology for data verifiability
- Worked on the majority of the codebase, from smart contracts, through Java backend to database integration and frontend development.
- Improved efficiency of the smart contracts used for storing data hashes on-chain.
- Monitored and measured backend performance. Identified bottlenecks and rewrote code for improved throughpu
- Skills acquired: Smart contract development in Solidity, Java performance monitoring and improvements, backend blockchain interactions (ethereum, hyperledger sawtooth), Geth, C#, cryptography, multi-threaded Java development, frontend development using React.js
- Technologies used: Java, Yourkit, blockchains (Ethereum, Hyperledger Sawtooth, Celo, Ganache), databases (Postgres, MongoDB, Apache Cassandra), Websockets, Docker, Kafka, RabbitMQ, React.js

Coherent Solutions

Jun. 2021 - Mar, 2022

- · work on microservices for supporting call center automation. Maintenance and continuous support for legacy components.
- Experience: main focus was designing and developing from scratch a Spring Boot application acting as a Workforce Manager (WFM) to be integrated with the rest of the infrastructure.
- Extras: developed tools for extracting meaningful information from logs for analytics.
- Technologies used: Spring Boot, Hibernate, Junit, SonarCube, maven, git, Jenkins, Windows OS, OAuth

Flow Traders

JAVA SOFTWARE ENGINEER Oct 2019 - June 2021

- · Responsibilities: develop and design microservices supporting daily trading activities involving coding of systems for receiving market data and placing orders, handling data in a reliable, performant and traceable manner.
- Skills acquired: writing object-oriented code to high quality standards based on best recommendations and best practices; software analysis and design using design patterns and concurrency patterns; critical thinking and refactoring; scoping and estimation skills; effective communication skills (verbal and written) in team and across the teams;
- Tech stack: Java, Kafka, gRPC, Junit, SonarCube, maven, git, Bamboo Oracle Database, Linux OS, React

Paddy Power Betfair

JAVA DEVELOPER May. 2019 - Oct. 2019

- Responsibilities: develop microservices related to login, user session management, session caching and user authentication for a complex web application; use of continuous integration and deployment approaches; write well designed, testable, efficient code; ensure quality of product, by extensive code reviews; ensure designs and implementation are in compliance with specifications
- Skills acquired: object oriented analysis and design using design patterns; refactoring; scoping and estimation skills; effective communication skills (verbal and written);
- Tech stack: Java, Spring, Cougar framework, Kafka, Junit, Tomcat, chef, maven, git, TargetProcess, Jenkins, Oracle Database, MacOS

ITIVITI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER jun. 2018 - apr. 2019

- · Responsibilities: design and develop a financial application; continuous contribution in all phases of the development lifecycle; write well designed, testable, efficient code; ensure quality of product, by extensive code reviews; ensure designs and implementation are in compliance with specifications
- Skills acquired: object oriented analysis and design using design patterns; refactoring; scoping and estimation skills; effective communication skills (verbal and written);
- Technologies used: Java, Groovy, C#, Junit, Spock, git, Gerrit, Gradle, Jenkins, JIRA

TORA Trading Services

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Aug. 2016 - Jun. 2018

- · Responsibilities: design and develop a financial application; continuous contribution in all phases of the development lifecycle; write well designed, testable, efficient code; ensure designs and implementation are in compliance with specifications
- · Skills acquired: object oriented analysis and design using common design patterns; scoping and estimation skills; effective communication skills (verbal and written); UNIX OS; profiling
- · Technologies used: Java, JUnit, git, Yourkit, Apache ant

Honors & Awards

- 2012 Gold medal, "Ariel" International Mathematical Team Olympiad
- Bronze medal, "Ariel" International Mathematical Team Olympiad
- Bronze medal, Catalysts Coding Contest 2016

Education

APRIL 18, 2024

Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Cluj-Napoca, Romania

Oct. 2016 - Jul. 2018

Oct. 2012 - Jul. 2016

Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Cluj-Napoca, Romania

BOLDIZSÁR KOVÁCS · RESUME